Georgia Hobson, Web developer and Marketer.

<u>Ghobs987@qmail.com</u> 07947128426

Profile

With a proven track record in sales, extensive experience of customer service, a background in Optical Management. Coupled with my 2:1 in Marketing. I possess both the virtues of my academic success and merits of well cultivated interpersonal skills.

Since graduating in 2019 my first career opportunity came in care, my desire to help those most in need and drive to make a difference led me to take a role I was vastly over qualified for. My ambition to take the next step in my career saw me return to education in May 2021 enrolled in the University of Birmingham's six month Web development bootcamp. Driven by a desire to develop the hard skills that will help me realise my vision for the future, I resigned from my role in care to take a sideways step into Gardening. A move that increased my flexibility and better positioned me for success at BIrmingham University.

As my course begins, I look to strike while the Iron is hot and start my career in web development!

Current Employment

Original Landscapes March 21- current Gardener

As a result of my desire to upskill and develop my career I left Helping hands for an employer who provided me with the flexibility to return to education at the University of BIrmingham, to undertake their Coding Bootcamp in May 21. My Role at Original Landscapes see's me responsible for.

- Customer experience management. With regards to negotiating work, time frames and quality.
- Manual Labour with a high attention to detail and health and safety compliance. With a focus on garden maintenance, construction and site maintenance.
- Social media Marketing. Utilising platforms such as Facebook and Instagram, for content curation based on identified Market segments.

Previous Employment

Helping Hands June 2020 to May 21

Live In Carer

In response to the Corvid pandemic and limited job opportunities I decided to retrain to help those who need it most. Within the Care Sector I enjoy a high level of personal reward through combining my customer service skills, planning and organising with a high level of autonomy and responsibility as well as ensuring a high level of care to clients to ensure their safety, well being and providing companionship.

Key achievement and skills

- Excellent experience of implementing bespoke customer service to meet individual client needs.
- Planning, organising, time management, and time tabling are essential requirements to provide structure and framework as well as the flexibility to respond to unique circumstances as they arise.
- communication and customer relationship development in a difficult and complicated time, with clients with a complex and broad set of communication difficulties. Communication to key stakeholders, the family, medical support services.
- Ensuring all compliance and regulatory requirements are met including accurate record keep and logging.

From September 2016 to July 2019 I studied at Salford University I sponsored myself to undertake this study and achieved a 2:1 degree

Eye Contact Opticians May 2014- September 2016 Senior Consultant/Manager

Joining Eye Contact, a busy independent boutique Optician based in Central London, provided the opportunity to gain experience in all commercial aspects of the business in an entrepreneurial environment. My success in the role led to my nomination for optical consultant of the year in opticians weekly.

Key achievements and skills

- Management, leadership and support of a small and results focused team
- Identifying opportunities for business growth and their implementation
- data management integrating CRM systems and Excel.
- Relationship management of key clients. Providing a personalised service to Corporate and Individual Clients

Boots opticians May 2011-October 2014 Senior Optical Consultant

Internal transfer and promotion from the Oxford store, to the prestigious Canary Wharf branch. My skills and experience as the most senior sales colleague were key to the success of the team in terms of initial set up and the Branch performance.

Key achievements and skills

- Champion of hero products such as Zeiss
- Management responsibilities in manager's absence, training and development of colleagues. Provide feedback to colleagues and help them to develop.
- At the Oxford City store managed and developed the Polaris account to achieve significant revenue and account growth.
- Selected to undertake a management skills course as part of a planned career progression into management.

Qualifications

BSc Marketing 2019 2.1 Salford University A Levels; History B, Politics B, Economics C As Levels; Geography C

GCSE's 9 A*-C including English and Maths

Computer Skills

Familiar with both Mac and Microsoft OS, including Microsoft Office (word, Excel), Creative Studio, Social Media Marketing, Google analytics.

Web development skills

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, Java, Git

Languages

English, Conversational Arabic, Mandarin and Spanish

Data Analytics

Whilst working at Eye Contact, my success in the role led to me becoming an important decision maker. My drive for success and attention to detail ment I engaged with a plethora of data. This ranged from detailed client information, google analytics, digital channel KPI's to extensive product databases.

It was my role to work with the marketing team to identify and target potential clients, monitor the performance of our existing customer offers across a range of KPI's. I would then laise and report back to the team, with a view to improving sales performance.

My interest in digital marketing and my eye for an opportunity resulted in my involvement in website and digital channel development. I selected and introduced new products to our online portfolio, the KPI's across which success was measured meant I used google analytics to monitor performance and produce reports which I presented regularly to the director.

My familiarity with Xcel and my strong numeracy skills, gave me the opportunity to be responsible for interpreting extensive and technical data books. With the responsibility of identifying the right product and setting the price to then integrate them to our digital platforms as well as our CRM systems.

Critical thinking

In my professional career it has always been important to me to take ownership and think holistically about my actions and their impact upon the business. My drive for success has resulted in me identifying possible opportunities, evaluating their ROI and selecting the right ones for the business. Through client feedback and market research I noticed an opportunity for bespoke clip on sunglasses. I negotiated the supply contract, helped design advertising for our digital platforms and targeted email marketing. Post launch I then

assisted with SEO and then used KPI's to evaluate long term inclusion in our product portfolio.

Problem solving

My proudest achievement in my career was to reduce order time by 33% and costs by 10% (£900aprox) per month through the same initiative. When I initially joined Eye contact, customer service reporting highlighted our order time was damaging our brand image. I decided to introduce new technology to the business, this required me to undertake training of numerous staff members and develop relationships with suppliers to install the manufacturing equipment. The successful integration of this technology enabled us to remove a costly part of our supply chain and reduce order time!

References

James Hartley 07773653979 current employer

Tutor at Birmingham University